kevinkeegans@gmail.com +353-876428470

Kevin Keegan Dublin, Ireland

www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-keegan-engineer

SUMMARY

Electronic Engineer with 5 years of industry experience.

Currently a senior member of the digital design team in the AMS group at AMD.

1st Class Honours Masters degree in Electronic & Computer Engineering from University College Dublin.

Experienced with System Verilog, Python, C, Linux.

Interested primarily in Digital Signal Processing & and RTL design.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages/Tools: Verilog, System Verilog, Python, Bash, MATLAB, C, Git, Perforce, LATEX.
- Operating Systems: Proficient in Linux and Windows environments.
- Digital Design: Experienced in:
 - o Frontend RTL Design
 - Power/Area & Timing Optimization
 - CDC Techniques
 - Real Number Modelling
 - o Digital Down Converter Implementations
 - o Linting (spyglass)
- Digital Signal Processing: Knowledgeable in:
 - Spectrum Analysis
 - o Digital Filtering
 - o Digital Communication Theory

Professional Experience

AMD, Wireless and Wired Group

Dublin, Ireland

Senior Digital Design Engineer

May 2021 - Present

- o ASIC Front-End Digital Design
- Played a key role as one of the lead design engineers on the ADC in RFSOC
- Block Owner for the Digital Down Converter
- Implemented new features for a highly configurable system of polyphase decimation filters
- Led the design of a complex equalizer
- Successfully integrated and brought up a channelizer
- Implemented digital blocks responsible for calibrating various components in the analog portion of the ADC.
- \circ Mentored interns in 2022 & 2023, overseeing their progress on a filter design project
- o Implementing real number models of analog blocks in System Verilog to aid digital verification
- $\circ~$ Provided extensive support to the verification team & other design engineers
- Developed a Python script to enhance the team's analysis of the ADC's performance,

Dialog Semiconductor, ASIC & IP Division

Digital Design Engineer

Jan 2020 - April 2021

Dublin, Ireland

- o Front-End Digital Design
- o Designed a CIC based anti-aliasing filter
- Developed scripts to automatically generate a Verilog implementation of a frequently redesigned block, along with its System Verilog testbench.

Susquehanna International Group (SIG)

Dublin, Ireland

Market Data Engineer

Sept 2018 - Nov 2019

- Monitoring and maintaining critical market data systems.
- Pcap file analysis via Wireshark/tshark
- Developed validation tools to test new software before pushing to production.
- Implemented a system in Python & Bash to archive daily market data recordings from company colocations to a central archive.
- o On call work. When on call, I was the first point of contact for issues regarding SIG's market data infrastructure.

Intel Corporation, Internet of Things and Wearables Group

Kildare, Ireland

Physical Design Engineer Intern

Jan 2017 - Aug 2017

• Developed a tool in TCL to automate the design, layout & routing of a custom CMOS block.

University College Dublin Voluntary Teaching Assistant

Dublin, Ireland

Sept 2015 - Nov 2015

• Voluntary Teaching Assistant in weekly laboratories for the engineering module, EEEN20010 Computer Engineering I: Data Structures and Algorithms through C.

FireEye, Inc.

Dublin, Ireland

Software Engineer Intern

May 2015 - July 2015

- o Developed BASH scripts to facilitate and automate product testing.
- Built a customized, kickstarted centOS distro to include the configurations and packages necessary for running & testing a company product.

EDUCATION

University College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

Master of Engineering in Electronic & Computer Engineering; 1st Class Honours

Sept 2016 - Sept 2018

- o **GPA**: 3.84/4.2
- UCD Intel Masters Scholarship: Awarded by Intel to top five students entering ME program.

University of California Los Angeles

Los Angeles, CA

Exchange - Electrical & Electronic Engineering; GPA: 3.18/4.0

Jan 2016 - Jun 2016

University College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

Bachelor of Science in Electrical & Electronic Engineering; 1st Class Honours

Sept 2013 - Sept 2016

- **GPA**: 4.09/4.2
- Entrance Scholar: Awarded to top academic achievers entering UCD from secondary school.

Coláiste Eoin

Dublin, Ireland

Irish Leaving Certificate; Points: 595 Sept 2007 – Jun 2013